hi spring fans welcome to another
嗨，春季粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this one
在这一部分中的Spring 提示
we're going to look at the you know the
我们将看看您知道的
question I'm often given which is hey I
我经常被问到哪个问题
have a brand new application I'm using
我正在使用一个全新的应用程序
the new reactive support that you know
您知道的新的反应式支持
you've hopefully heard me talk about
你希望听到我谈论
last two-plus odd years and the spring
最近的两个多奇年和 Spring
team at large and you've seen know
整个团队，您已经知道
countless blogs on the spring L blog and
春季L博客和
a good deal many videos on on the topic
有关该主题的很多视频
from the various conferences from the
来自各种会议
spring one platform shows I mean not to
Spring 一个平台表明我的意思是不
mention you know literally hundreds of
提到你真的知道数百
conferences around the world I mean
我的意思是世界各地的会议
hopefully at this point you're persuaded
希望在这一点上你被说服
right I hope that you can appreciate
对，我希望你能体谅
that reactive programming gives you the
反应式编程为您提供了
ability to build better software faster
能够更快地构建更好的软件
it gives you the ability rather to more
它给了您更多的能力
precisely more technically build
确切地说是在技术上
applications that take advantage of
利用以下优势的应用程序
asynchronous i/o to support better
异步I / O，以更好地支持
throughput better uhsorry better
吞吐能力更好
scalability so you can handle more
可扩展性，因此您可以处理更多
transactions with the same computer
使用同一台计算机进行交易
because you're no longer sitting on a
因为你不再坐在
given thread monopolizing a thread
给定线程垄断一个线程
making it impossible for others to use
使其他人无法使用
it by doing this you're able to build
通过这样做您就可以构建
software that can handle more users
可以处理更多用户的软件
right with the same with the same cost
权利相同，成本相同
or you can you can have your data center
或者您可以拥有数据中心
built right instead of doubling the
建立正确，而不是加倍
number of users you can have it I'm
你可以拥有的用户数量
using you know 1/2 + 2 X as simple
使用您知道1/2 + 2 X一样简单
numbers but the point is you can either
数字，但关键是你可以
handle more users for the same cost or
以相同的费用处理更多的用户，或者
you can handle the same users for less
您可以花更少的钱处理相同的用户
cost right and that's the that's one of
成本权，那就是其中之一
the big benefits here and it allows you
这里最大的好处，它可以让你
to scale out right it allows you to
正确扩展它可以使您
handle a greater capacity of a greater
处理更大的能力
number of requests and this is
请求数，这是
particularly important when you move to
当您移至
micro services into IOT into Big Data
微服务转变为物联网转变为大数据
where you've got an increasingly larger
你的地方越来越大
amount of data being connected over the
通过连接的数据量
network through network buffers in terms
通过网络缓冲区来表示网络
of input and output reactive programming
输入和输出无功编程
is all about input and output all about
全部关于输入和输出
I mean it's I suppose you could talk
我的意思是我想你可以说
about some of the other use cases right
关于其他一些用例吧
there's a the the fact that reactive
有一个事实，即反应性
programming gives you the ability to
编程使您能够
better reason about errors in your
关于您的错误的更好原因
processing flow you know the stream of
您知道的处理流程
data it gives you a functional style way
数据，为您提供实用的样式方式
to make it seem to date as well that's
使它看起来也是如此
more elegant and
更优雅和
it gives you a compositional model
它给你一个构图模型
that's based on the decoupling of or the
是基于或的解耦
sort of separation of the assembly of
某种程度的组装分离
the processing pipeline from the
来自
subscription of the pipe processing
订阅管道处理
pipeline we say that that the Assembly
管道，我们说，大会
of the pipeline is is cold right it's a
的管道很冷，对
cold stream of data it's like it's like
冷数据流就像
a series of pipes that have been
一系列的管道已经
connected together but until you pour
连接在一起但直到倒
water into those pipes
把水倒进那些管子里
that's the subscription or execution
那是订阅或执行
time then we say that that is a cold
时间，然后我们说那是感冒
stream when it once there's water in the
当它里面有水时流
pipes then it's a hot stream right
管道，然后是热流吧
you're in now in execution time so you
您现在处于执行时间，所以您
define the pipeline data goes through it
定义管道数据通过它
and then these two things can happen
然后这两件事可能发生
separately you can define the pipeline
您可以分别定义管道
now and then the data can flow through
数据有时会流过
the pipeline an hour from now right the
从现在开始一个小时的管道
the benefit of that is that there's an
这样做的好处是
opportunity there to intervene right you
有机会干预你
can actually you can actually have the
可以实际上您可以拥有
operators you can have the scheduler you
操作员，您可以安排调度员
can have the framework that's aware of
可以拥有知道的框架
this pipeline and it's aware of how
这个管道，它知道如何
these things stick together
这些东西粘在一起
you can have it intervene on your behalf
您可以代表您进行干预
and so it can reassemble things it can
这样它就可以重新组装东西
add extra steps for example for auditing
添加额外的步骤，例如进行审核
or for debugging it can do all sorts of
或进行调试，它可以做各种
interesting things it can also rearrange
有趣的事情也可以重新排列
things if it sees possible optimizations
看到可能的优化的事情
and might be able to fuse certain
并且可能能够融合某些
operators that would be you know two
你可能会知道两个运算符
steps that could be made into one
可以合二为一的步骤
because you've got sort of a makeshift
因为你有一个临时的
compiler kind of thing going on behind
编译器发生的事情
the scenes they're not really but you
场景不是真的，但是你
there's optimizations all right so
有优化就可以了
there's a lot of opportunities by moving
搬家有很多机会
to reactive programming and by moving to
进行反应式编程并移至
a framework that gives you the ability
一个给你能力的框架
to think about things in this way and
用这种方式思考事情，
because of that you also have this more
因此，你也有更多
interesting opportunity in a single
一次有趣的机会
place to sort of deal with and think
进行思考和思考的地方
about errors there's also the the I
关于错误，还有我
think it's a natural way to think about
认为这是一种自然的思考方式
integration because if you have to think
整合，因为如果您必须考虑
about how you interact with different
关于如何与他人互动
systems it's if you had to pick one
系统，如果您必须选择一个
modality pick a synchronous right I want
方式选择我想要的同步权利
to connect two different types of data
连接两种不同类型的数据
out there some systems are easily
那里有些系统很容易
integrated with in terms of a
与...整合
synchronous API and some are easily
同步API，有些很容易
integrated in a asynchronous API but you
集成在异步API中，但是您
cannot you cannot synthesize or fake
你不能不能合成或伪造
of blocking interactions I'm sorry non
阻止互动的问题，对不起，
blocking interactions you can't fake a
阻止无法伪造的互动
synchronous interactions with
与...同步互动
asynchronous integration so if I want to
异步集成，所以如果我想
talk to something that publishes
谈论出版的东西
messages asynchronously there's no way
异步消息是不可能的
to do that except for asynchronously on
做到这一点，除了异步
the other hand if I want to take
另一方面，如果我想服用
something that that is asynchronous and
异步的东西
then consume it in a blocking way I can
然后以阻塞的方式消耗它
do that I can simulate that right so if
这样做我可以正确模拟，所以如果
you have to pick one type pick
你必须选择一种类型
asynchronous first and so when you're
首先异步，所以当你
dealing with the reactor API and with
处理反应堆API和
reactive API you're dealing with
您正在处理的反应式API
asynchronous API and this gives you a
异步API，这为您提供了
nice way to you know model the world you
认识世界的好方法
can deal with the world in terms of this
可以在这个方面与世界打交道
one kind of stuff this reactive stream
一种反应流
of data so whether you're talking to a
数据，因此无论您是在与
REST API or to getting data from a
REST API或从中获取数据
database or doing messaging or you're
数据库或进行消息传递，或者您正在
doing WebSockets or you're doing
在做WebSockets或在做
application JSON just five records you
应用JSON仅五条记录
know whatever you're doing you can deal
知道你在做什么就可以应付
with it in terms of this publisher API
就此发布者API而言
that is core to the reactive streams
这是反应流的核心
spec okay and you can deal with it in
规格还可以，您可以在其中处理
terms of the operators that come with
附带的运营商条款
reactor and reactor makes it easy to
电抗器和电抗器使其易于
build these sort of reactive
建立这种反应性
applications and I've talked a good deal
应用程序，我已经谈了很多
about all this stuff before I don't
关于所有这些东西，在我不这样做之前
really want to get too deep into that
真的很想深入了解
but in this installment of spring tips
但在本期 spring 技巧 中
my friends we're going to look at what
我的朋友们，我们来看看
it is to build applications that are
它是建立应用程序
reactive and and what it is to debug
反应性以及调试的内容
them right what are some of the
他们正确的是一些
opportunities we have for isolating
我们有机会隔离
issues in our reactive applications
反应性应用程序中的问题
because as I've just established
因为正如我刚刚确定的
reactive applications are at least in
反应性应用至少在
terms of the program model asynchronous
程序模型术语异步
by default so we're gonna build an
默认情况下，我们将建立一个
application here to start spring that
在这里申请开始 Spring
i/o we're gonna call this debugging
I / O我们将称之为调试
reactor okay and we're just gonna use
反应堆好了，我们将使用
I'm gonna use the reactive web support I
我要使用反应式网络支持
don't really want the web server I don't
真的不想要我不想要的网络服务器
care about the web server I just want
关心我只想要的Web服务器
something that'll bring in reactor and
会带进反应堆的东西
all that stuff with it and and also this
所有这些东西，还有这个
has the benefit of starting up a web
具有启动网络的好处
server and so it'll keep the Java
服务器，因此它将保留Java
process running otherwise my
进程运行否则我的
asynchronous API is which are you know
您知道异步API
they're not they won't keep the process
他们不是，他们不会继续这一过程
running unless I do something to make
除非我做点什么才能跑步
them old demons so I'll just use that to
他们是老恶魔，所以我只用它来
get around that issue okay and then
解决这个问题好吧，然后
we're just gonna hit generate there we
我们只是要点击生成我们
go okay so I think this might be the
好的，所以我认为这可能是
simplest
最简单的
demo in terms of dependencies that I've
根据我所拥有的依赖关系进行演示
ever done for you my fine friends so
曾经为你做过我的好朋友，所以
that's kind of cut that's kind of
那是割伤
interesting now that I think of it I
我现在想起来很有趣
didn't even had Lombok how cool is that
甚至没有龙目岛那有多酷
I should maybe I should have ad in
我也许应该在其中放广告
Lombok I don't know you'll see that I'll
龙目岛我不知道你会看到我会
add some dependencies so maybe I
添加一些依赖关系，也许我
shouldn't get ahead of myself what we're
我们不应该超越自己
gonna do is to just demonstrate some of
要做的只是展示一些
the opportunities here for debugging
调试的机会
things with IntelliJ what we want there
IntelliJ做的事情我们想要在那里
we go
我们去
there's my application what what is uh
我的应用程序是什么
here we go we want to make our lives
我们要走了，我们要生活
easier
更轻松
right and I'll be the first to admit
对，我将是第一个承认
that moving to an asynchronous world
转移到异步世界
where execution of processing can jump
处理的执行可以跳到哪里
from one thread to another with with
从一个线程到另一个
ease and almost shocking trend you know
你知道缓解和几乎令人震惊的趋势
sort of opaqueness can be a bit daunting
有点不透明可能会让人望而生畏
at first right especially if you're not
首先，尤其是如果您不是
used to functional programming if you're
习惯于函数式编程（如果您
not used to functional programming that
不习惯函数编程
can be its own ordeal moving from from
可能是从
non-functional imperative programming to
非功能命令式编程
functional programming that's his own
他自己的函数式编程
thing and then to double down on that to
事情然后再加倍
make it even more daunting I suppose for
我想让它变得更加艰巨
some people is the fact that it's all
有些人就是这一切
asynchronous as well so you've got you
异步的，所以你有你
know the movement of work across
知道工作的移动
different thread boundaries to contend
争用不同的线程边界
with as well and that can make it
与以及可以做到这一点
difficult tonight and I know what you're
今晚很难，我知道你是什么
thinking at this point I oh you know GE
在这一点上，我想你知道GE
and what what could you do to make this
你怎么做才能做到这一点
more difficult Josh I mean it sounds
乔希（Josh）更难
like this is gonna be one heck of an
像这样会成为一个
uphill climb and I don't think that's
上坡，我不认为那是
true I think it takes a little practice
是的，我认为这需要一些练习
and a little muscle memory to appreciate
还有一点肌肉记忆可以欣赏
the tool and the API and to start
该工具和API并开始
writing code just to see that yeah it
编写代码只是为了看到它
works the way you think it does and most
以您认为的方式运作，而且大多数
of the time if you don't know how it
如果你不知道的时候
works there's a friendly community or
在一个友好的社区工作，或者
you know an opera self-describing method
你知道歌剧自我描述的方法
you can call or something like that but
你可以打电话或类似的东西，但
it can be I suppose daunting right at
可能是我想在
first of the very first especially if
首先，特别是如果
you haven't done either of it and you
你都没有做过而你
might be thinking gee I you know I I'd
可能在想，我知道我会
rather move to the surface of the Sun I
宁愿移到太阳表面我
mean that seems easier this you might as
意味着这看起来更容易
well ask me to do that but it's not so
好问我这样做，但事实并非如此
bad right okay let's talk about let's
不好吧，好吧，让我们谈谈
talk about some of the obvious stuff
谈论一些明显的东西
okay so I've got an application it's
好，所以我有一个应用程序
gonna be a event listener and in the
将会成为事件监听器，并在
event listener I'm gonna listen for an
事件监听器，我要听一个
event the application ready event and
事件应用程序就绪事件，以及
this is just me
这就是我
starting up I'm just waiting for the
启动我只是在等待
application to start up and I'll run
应用程序启动，我将运行
some code and the code is just gonna be
一些代码，代码将是
trivial demo code that will work with
可以使用的简单演示代码
you okay so let's see some of the other
你还好，让我们来看看其他一些
opportunities here
这里的机会
first of all let's say that I want to
首先，我想说
generate a stream of data so I'll say
生成数据流，所以我会说
flex dot generate or actually better yet
弹性点生成或实际上更好
flex that just and what I'm doing is I'm
证明那是公正的，而我正在做的是
creating a reactive type here okay i'm
在这里创建一个反应类型，好吧
creating a a publisher that supports 0
创建一个支持0的发布商
to X records that's a flux
到X记录的流量
monos support interactive type and it
Monos支持交互式类型，它
supports 0 or 1 record ok so these are
支持0或1条记录，所以这些是
both from reactor they both implement
两者都来自反应堆
the publisher interface from the
的发布者界面
reactive stream specification they both
他们都反应流规格
publish streams of data to subscribers
向订阅者发布数据流
and those subscribers can be on
这些订阅者可以在
different threads and the publication of
不同的线程和出版物
the data can also happen in a separate
数据也可以单独发生
thread so I'm just gonna create a b c d
线程，所以我要创建abcd
e yeah okay just a stream of letters and
是的，好吧，只是一连串的信件和
now what i'm gonna do is i want to log i
现在我要做的是我要登录我
guess the most obvious thing you can do
猜猜你可以做的最明显的事情
to debug stuff is you can use to
调试东西是你可以用来
subscribe right you guys subscribe and
订阅你们的订阅权，
subscribe is a by default if you use the
如果您使用
reactive stream specification
反应流规格
implementation subscribe it takes a
实现订阅需要一个
subscriber and subscriber is a bit of a
订户和订户有点
verbose interface you can see that here
详细的界面，您可以在这里看到
right so subscriber and then there's on
对，所以订户，然后有
subscribe there's on next there's on
订阅接下来是
error and on complete i don't want you
错误，总的来说，我不要你
to be in the business of writing
从事写作
subscribers i probably don't need to
订户，我可能不需要
most of the time instead using use one
大多数时候使用一个
of the overload method
重载方法
so here's consumer and that takes i can
所以这是消费者，我可以
you know that takes the string parameter
你知道这需要字符串参数
which is the letter you know that we've
你知道我们已经收到的那封信
expressed here and it allows you to do
在这里表达，它可以让你做
something with it so i'm gonna I should
有东西，所以我应该
have brought Lombok oh I already regret
带了龙目岛哦，我已经后悔了
it okay private final you know what I'm
好的，私人决赛，你知道我是什么
gonna bring in Lombok I'm that kind of
要带龙目岛我就是那种
guy I am that lazy I'd rather add a
家伙，我很懒，我宁愿加一个
dependency then write the extra code so
然后编写额外的代码
long for J no wrong one Lombok good
渴望J没有错一个龙目岛好
stuff ok did you see how I kind of like
好吧，你看到我怎么样了吗
just sung
刚唱歌
I just sung the word long buck and then
我只唱了长钱这个词，然后
almost as if by magic it it kind of
几乎就像是魔术般
appeared that was kind of cool I don't
看起来很酷，我不喜欢
know whatever
知道什么
anyway um log4j - thank you
无论如何um log4j-谢谢
good stuff now there's my logger and I
好东西，现在有我的记录器，我
can now log this out no letter left er
现在可以注销了，没有字母了
all right good stuff huh good stuff so
好东西好吧
there's this and I'm just logging the
有这个，我只是在记录
data but what if there's an error what
数据，但是如果有错误怎么办？
if I want to what if I have some sort of
如果我想要某种东西的话
error here so let's say let's say that
这里的错误，所以让我们说
I'm gonna do a map I'm gonna say okay
我要去做一张地图我要说好
well or better yet I'll do it I'll do a
好还是更好，但我会做到的
map and in the map I'm gonna throw an
地图，然后在地图上
exception okay so okay if X its letter
异常好吧，如果X是它的字母，那么好吧
if letter dot e equals a block of course
如果字母点e等于当然
okay equals F then return I'm going to
好吧等于F然后返回我要去
do flat map here then return mono error
在这里做平面地图然后返回单声道错误
legal and let's say static class illegal
合法的，比如说静态类是非法的
letter exception for some reason I've
由于某种原因造成的信件异常
chose to make it very hard to have the
选择让很难
letter F in a stream I don't know why
流中的字母F我不知道为什么
whatever it doesn't actually matter we
不管实际上不重要，我们
just want some sort of error case okay
只想要某种错误情况就可以了
so we'll say new illegal letter
所以我们会说新的非法信件
exception all right and good stuff
例外，没事，好东西
okay good stuff
好东西
so actually we don't even need that okay
所以实际上我们甚至不需要
so when throw that we're just gonna
所以当我们扔的时候
assume if it's an F it should always
假设它是F，则应始终
throw an error and that's fine else
抛出一个错误，那还可以
we're gonna say return monotype just
我们要说返回单字型
letter so I'm gonna return I'll keep
信，所以我要回来，我会继续
every letter except for F which I for
除F以外的所有字母
some reason arbitrarily just really
任意原因只是真的
don't like okay so we're gonna get rid
不喜欢，所以我们要摆脱
of that and would keep monitor mine up
其中，并会继续监视我的
you know letter otherwise so good stuff
你知道字母，否则好东西
so now I've actually just flat map the
所以现在我实际上只是将地图
data I've got a pipe by name by the way
数据我顺便说一句
this is what we mean let's say we got a
这就是我们的意思，假设我们有一个
we've got a cold stream right so I'm
我们的河很冷，所以我
actually creating a cold Steam here my
实际上在这里产生冷的蒸汽
letters so there you go I've got a cold
信件，所以你去了，我感冒了
stream if I subscribe to it suddenly it
流，如果我突然订阅它
becomes hot stream right I'm subscribing
我正在订阅时变得热门
to it
对此
you can actually take something that is
你实际上可以服用一些
a cold stream and turn it into a hot
冷流变成热
stream so basically a cold stream means
流，所以基本上是冷流意味着
that it's an empty pipeline and nothing
那是一条空管道，一无所有
is flowing through it yet and so you
正在流过它，所以你
know it would replay the entire pipeline
知道它将重播整个管道
from the beginning and start from flux
从一开始就从通量开始
just a and then flatmap and then you
只是一个，然后是平面图，然后您
know whatever right and keep going
知道什么权利，然后继续前进
through the operators I could do filters
通过运营商，我可以做过滤器
and all that kind of stuff it would do
以及它会做的所有事情
that each time you subscribed for
每次您订阅
example or each time you called block or
示例或每次您调用阻止或
each time you called any of these things
每次你打电话给这些东西
that sort of end up having the effect of
最终会产生
pouring water in the pipes basically and
基本上在管道里倒水，
that's you know that's the that's that's
那是你知道那是那是那
when it becomes a hot stream now in this
现在当它成为热门
case I've got a cold stream you can
如果我流得很冷，你可以
actually take a cold stream and create
其实很冷，创造
another cold stream that that's actually
实际上是另一条冷流
a hot stream kind of so for one example
例如一个热流
is that you can say letters dot share
是你可以说字母点分享
and in this case it wouldn't replay from
在这种情况下，它不会从
the beginning because what share does is
开始是因为份额所做的是
now when subscriber subscribes to this
现在，当订户订阅此
like this share that subscribe they can
喜欢这些可以订阅的共享
actually extract this out
实际提取出来
String consumer so now when we when we
字符串消费者，所以当我们当我们
log the data good stuff there you go so
记录数据的好东西，你去吧
now when we log the data you see that
现在，当我们记录数据时，您会看到
this is the shared subscriber well
这是共享订户
actually see possibly you know be only
其实看到也许你知道只有
you won't see a at all it's actually
您根本看不到一个
going to get the live stream of data
将获得实时数据流
okay one way I could guarantee this is
好吧，我可以保证的一种方法是
by delaying the data right I can
通过延迟数据我可以
actually stagger it out a little bit so
实际上错开了一点
I can say delay elements duration of
我可以说延迟元素的持续时间
second one and then I can say thread
第二个，然后我可以说线程
sleep two times this there you go and so
睡两次，你去那里等等
now in theory I should only see you know
从理论上讲，我现在应该只会看到你知道
maybe B but possibly not but you know
也许是B但可能不是，但你知道
cdef that's right so out of the shared
cdef是正确的，所以脱离共享
one okay and that's because share
好的，那是因为分享
doesn't reach doesn't replay the entire
达不到不会重播整个
pipeline and it's not starting the
管道，它没有启动
processing again it's actually tapping
再次处理它实际上是在点击
into an existing sort of in-flight
进入现有的机上
stream of data okay so I hope that helps
数据流还可以，所以希望对您有所帮助
that back that's not actually what I was
那不是我原来的样子
trying to show you here but it does help
试图向您展示这里，但确实有帮助
you hopefully appreciate some of the
您希望能欣赏其中的一些
benefits of you know assembly versus
您知道组装的好处与
execution okay all right so let's let's
执行好吧，好吧，让我们
run this what do we get huh let's happen
运行这个，我们得到什么，让我们发生吧
what happens if we run this program
如果我们运行该程序会发生什么
okay
好的
so I got an illegal letter exception no
所以我收到了非法信件例外
s can't be an F right let's I think
我不能是F吧，我想
that's fair and and you can see the
那很公平，您可以看到
error you can see the exception there
错误，您可以在那里看到异常
now in this case the exception is in
现在在这种情况下例外
this case it's managed to bubble up to
在这种情况下，它设法冒出来
the top that may not always be the case
并非总是如此的顶部
and so you will want to subscribe to the
因此，您将要订阅
errors you can actually process the
您可以实际处理的错误
errors and that's you saw that before
错误，那就是您之前看到的
you saw a subscription or subscriber
您看到一个订阅或订阅者
from new metrics James Beck has a non
来自新指标James Beck的非
error method right on errors when we get
当我们得到错误时使用错误方法
any exceptions but we don't have a
任何例外，但我们没有
separate control phone mechanism right
单独的控制电话机制权利
this is any error is treated like data
这是任何错误都被视为数据
it's just like another kind of piece of
就像另一种
data just like on next so when we
数据就像下一个一样，所以当我们
subscribe to the data in the on error we
订阅错误中的数据我们
get that data and that stops the flow of
获取该数据，这将阻止
data through the pipeline it's not a kid
通过管道传输数据不是孩子
simple control flow we don't do try cat
简单的控制流程，我们不去尝试
wait because try-catch would be weird
等待，因为try-catch会很奇怪
right try-catch assumes everything is in
正确的try-catch假定一切都在
the same thread of execution that's not
相同的执行线程
what's happening here
这里发生了什么事
and so errors are handled in the stream
因此错误会在流中处理
itself we have an overloaded version of
本身，我们有一个超载版本
subscribed that takes it that handled
订阅处理
errors so you can see the second one is
错误，所以您可以看到第二个是
given a throwable log error okay and of
给定一个可抛出的日志错误，并且
course I can give it to that because it
我当然可以做到这一点，因为它
you know we know it will never make it
你知道我们知道它永远不会成功
that far so good stuff
到目前为止好东西
actually it occurs to me I could just
实际上发生在我身上，我可以
for our demo here make that simpler yeah
因为我们的演示使这一过程变得更简单
that's nice so now I'm saying log
很好，现在我要说的是日志
through we don't need the shared version
通过我们不需要共享版本
keep our demo simple okay so now we are
保持我们的演示简单简单，所以现在我们
I guess we could actually have a let's
我想我们实际上可以让我们
see void error throwable key log got
看到无效错误抛出键日志
info oh noes and then log got error tea
信息哦，是，然后记录错误茶
okay okay that's this so I'm going to
好的，就是这样，所以我要
now change it to this instead of log and
现在将其更改为此，而不是日志和
then that'll be everything else so we
那将是其他一切，所以我们
start this
开始这个
okay
好的
so
所以
there it is right there's our own oh so
那里是对的我们有自己的哦
that's the most obvious opportunity for
那是最明显的机会
us to work with an interactive errors
我们与互动错误一起工作
now in this case I've got you know
现在，在这种情况下，我知道了
everything's kind of just
一切都只是
straightforward it's a single it's a
直截了当这是一个单一的
single thread really at this point
此时确实是单线程
doesn't seem like it's moving across
看起来好像没有移动
different threads but you could move it
不同的线程，但您可以移动它
across difference right you can actually
跨不同的权利，你实际上可以
say I want to publish this on a
说我想将其发布在
different schedule
不同的时间表
all right so scheduler dot elastic right
好的，所以调度程序点弹性正确
so you could do that
所以你可以做到
now what does it look like
现在看起来像什么
can't be an F lambda flatmap on next
下一个不能是Lambda平面图
debugging this it's not exactly clear
调试这还不是很清楚
did that work on it did that actually
确实做了那个工作
spit up a sip of thread I suppose I
我想我会a一口
should be logging the thread data so you
应该记录线程数据，所以你
can actually move execution from one
实际上可以将执行从一个
thread to another or you could do
线程到另一个，或者你可以做
instead of publish on you could say
而不是发布您可以说
subscribe on all right I'm gonna
订阅吧，我要
schedulers dot elastic and then the
调度程序点弹性，然后
second parameter is request on a
第二个参数是对
separate thread true and we'll run this
单独的线程true，我们将运行它
again
再次
okay so in theory the pipeline the the
好吧，理论上管道
threat of execution enacted we can we
颁布执行威胁，我们可以
can see that here the interior the
可以看到这里的内部
threat of execution is on a separate
执行威胁在另外一个地方
thread than the threat on which this was
线程比它所受到的威胁
launched okay I don't have a union
发射好了，我没有工会
loggers to see that let's see what's the
记录员看到，让我们看看是什么
best way to do that let's put a method
做到这一点的最佳方法，让我们提出一个方法
here void info string letter log info
此处无效信息字符串字母日志信息
the current value is letter okay and I
当前值是字母还可以，我
want to log also the name so log that
还要记录名称，以便记录
info thread got current thread I get get
信息线程获得了当前线程我得到了
the name I'll do the same thing for the
我将为这个名称做同样的事情
error already
已经有错误
so there's this okay so there's my
这样就可以了
updated code let's restart this with
更新的代码，让我们重新启动
this instead of log info good we start
这而不是日志信息好，我们开始
okay so you can see now yes thread for
好的，所以您现在可以看到
the first you know the at some point
在某个时候你首先知道
we're on this thread elastic too and we
我们也在这条线上有弹性，我们
stay on elastic too and that's when we
保持弹性，那就是当我们
log out the error where you don't have
注销您没有的错误
the other items in the stream because
流中的其他项目，因为
you know this first stage gets run first
你知道这个第一阶段要先运行
so basically we're we're moving across
所以基本上我们在跨
different threads right we're moving on
不同的线程，我们正在前进
to different threads of execution for
到不同的执行线程
the processing of our data so what would
处理我们的数据，那会怎样
a stack trace look like right what would
堆栈跟踪看起来像正确的那样
a strategist actress look like if we if
一位战略家女演员看起来如果
we actually threw an exception what if I
我们实际上抛出了一个例外，如果我
had a null pointer what would that look
有一个空指针，那会是什么样子
like let's try that okay so instead of
就像让我们尝试一下，所以
doing a flat map which is a nice
做一个平面图，这是一个很好的
organized way to do it let's do dot map
有组织的方法来做点图
and L and I'll return L I'll say return
和L我会返回L我会说返回
L and I will say if L that equals F
L，我会说L是否等于F
throw to a null pointer or actually
抛出一个空指针或实际上
legal letter exception okay there's this
法律函件例外，好的，有这个
okay so that's basically the same result
好，基本上结果是一样的
right we can actually see that as well
对，我们实际上也可以看到
so okay a number of different ways to
好吧，有很多不同的方法
sort of see the data move through the
可以看到数据通过
pipeline we've created flat map and I
我们创建了平面图的管道，我
did I processed an error I've got and
我是否处理了我遇到的错误并
here I can actually if I wanted to I can
如果可以，我可以在这里我可以
include information about there in the
在其中包含有关的信息
arrow callback right whereas with this
向右箭头回调，与此同时
I'm just throwing an exception and the
我只是抛出一个异常，
framework captures it I could get
框架捕获了我可以得到的
bubbles up in the same way but it's
以相同的方式冒泡，但是
don't have a great picture for you know
没有一张好照片
you can see I've been trying to kind of
你可以看到我一直在努力
feel out where the data has been going
找出数据的去向
and how it's coming together and why it
以及如何融合在一起，为什么
arrives I can see the error I've been
到了我可以看到我曾经犯过的错误
very good about adding this exception
关于添加此异常非常好
having I've been very good about
我一直都很好
documenting what's happening here I've
记录我在这里发生的事情
got these callbacks and you know really
得到了这些回调，你真的知道
trying to give myself as much
尽力给自己
information as possible but I don't you
尽可能多的信息，但我不是
know if you looked at this right here
知道你是否在这里看过这个
you wouldn't have an appreciation for
你不会感激
this or possibly any other steps before
此步骤或之前的任何其他步骤
it right let's say I did map L all that
没错，我做了L映射
to lowercase right now let's do that
现在将其转换为小写字母
okay so now we have the extra step there
好吧，现在我们有多余的步骤了
and we're logging that out
我们正在将其注销
e F oh it's lowercase so that actually
哦，它是小写的，所以实际上
gets to er let's try that again sorry
不好意思，让我们再试一次，对不起
wrong test and now lower case just in
错误的测试，现在小写
case because I get back into that
的情况，因为我回到那个
trouble there we go so we've got the
麻烦我们去了，所以我们有
same issue you can see that we got to
同样的问题，您可以看到我们必须
the same error again but we didn't see
再次出现相同的错误，但我们没有看到
that there's several steps before we
在我们之前有几个步骤
don't know how this thing came together
不知道这东西是怎么在一起的
we don't know what the assembly of this
我们不知道这是什么组装
pipeline looks like and without that
管道看起来像没有那个
information we have no context to use in
我们没有上下文可使用的信息
debugging this we have to kind of just
调试它，我们不得不
puzzle at the code itself so one way you
对代码本身感到困惑，所以一种方式
can do this is to I suppose add debug
可以做到这一点是我想添加调试
information as we did kind of with the
信息，就像我们对
log in and on and all that stuff
登录并继续进行所有操作
another way to do that is to call dot
另一种方法是调用点
log so let's say dot log and you can
记录，所以说点记录，您可以
even plug in a logger or category or
甚至插入记录器或类别，或者
whatever if you want I'm just as the
随便你怎么想我都一样
default it's just rerun the same program
默认情况下，它只是重新运行同一程序
okay so here you can see that we can see
好的，所以在这里您可以看到我们可以看到
what happened we can see oh okay
发生了什么我们可以看到哦
the subsequently the subscribers
随后的订户
subscribed and was given a subscribe
已订阅并被订阅
subscription right and then we are
订阅权，然后我们
requesting a buffer so you by default
请求缓冲区，因此默认情况下您
the subscriber that we are you know the
我们是您的订户，您知道
wrapper around our consumer is a
包装我们的消费者是
subscriber that then requests 32 more
然后再请求32个订阅者
records at a time it's a small buffer
一次记录很小的缓冲区
obviously we don't need 32 records
显然我们不需要32条记录
we've only got you know maybe cdef right
我们只是让您知道cdef正确
and we can see that it processed on next
我们可以看到它在接下来的处理
up until II and it finally got to an on
一直到第二阶段
error when it came to something and we
当涉及到某些错误时，我们
know that it's an F right and obviously
知道这是F权利，显然
our exceptions fairly well so self
我们的例外情况很好，自我
documenting so that log information we
记录，以便我们记录信息
added up to the end of the pipeline and
加到管道的末尾
they gave us information about what
他们给我们有关什么的信息
happened right that's not bad by the way
发生的事情还不错，顺便说一句
instead of doing the SUBSCRIBE instead
而不是执行SUBSCRIBE
of doing that if you don't want to right
如果您不想做的话
now this like I I'm doing the on error
现在这就像我在做错误
thing here in the subscriber but that's
订户中的东西，但这是
not always the case is it I I might
并非总是这样
actually give let's say whenever method
实际上让我们说什么时候方法
here right so void process publisher
在这里，所以流程发布者无效
right and this will be a publisher of
对，这将是
type string could have been letters of
类型字符串可能是
their cars at this point I realize that
此时他们的车我意识到
now but hashtag Yolo okay so now what
现在，但是用标签Yolo好，那么现在
I'm gonna do I'm gonna say letters dot
我要说字母点
subscribe do I have to make the user
订阅我必须让用户
worry about that right what if I want to
担心那个权利，如果我想
have a built in thing that handles
有一个内置的东西可以处理
errors in the publisher right so here
发布商中的错误，所以在这里
I'm gonna let's see if I do this letters
我要看看我是否写这封信
dot pub you know whatever and so this is
点酒吧你知道什么，所以这是
the thing that's actually processing the
实际上正在处理的东西
data I don't know where this publisher
数据我不知道这个发布者在哪里
came from I didn't you know I don't want
来自我，你不知道我不要
to have to ask the user to remember to
必须要求用户记住
call the on error consumer to provide
呼叫错误使用者以提供
that when it uses this so one waited to
当它使用这个，所以一个人等待
do that to build it into the pipeline is
这样做将其构建到管道中是
to add it as an error do one error
将其添加为错误，则执行一个错误
callback so here I can say I do on error
回调，所以在这里我可以说我做错了
and you get the same opportunity okay
你会得到同样的机会
so this dot ever doable same exact code
所以这个点可以做相同的确切代码
cool so now this is no longer required
很酷，所以现在不再需要
it will have a non error callback no
它将有一个非错误的回调
matter of what whether the publisher
不管发行人是什么
whether the subscriber knows to provide
订户是否知道要提供
one or not so if you get in there you
一个或不，所以如果你进入那里，你
can have some generic lot you know
可以有一些通用的东西，你知道
generic behavior in there we could
那里的一般行为
actually contribute like some sort of
实际上像某种贡献
pre-processing that looks at all
看起来很预处理
publishers that are creating
正在创建的发布者
organization and that then you know
组织，然后你知道
instruments it to do the right thing
仪器做正确的事
there so lots of opportunities good
那里有很多机会
stuff okay okay so we're back to where
东西好吧好吧，我们回到了那里
we were we can see that with the the log
我们当时可以通过日志看到
operations we get visibility into what's
操作中，我们可以了解什么
happening I like that but I am also
发生我喜欢那样，但我也
leery of the fact that this stack trace
对堆栈跟踪的事实持怀疑态度
isn't really helpful I mean it is in
不是真的有帮助，我的意思是
this case it seems to be okay
这种情况似乎还可以
but if I move to work from one thread to
但是如果我将工作从一个线程转移到
another if I did things like that if I
如果我做了类似的事情，如果我
had parts of the application that were
包含部分应用程序
if I had parts of the interaction that
如果我有部分互动
happened on different threads then
然后发生在不同的线程上
things would become kind of difficult
事情会变得困难
right so let's say I wanted to let's say
对，所以我想说
that I wanted to now get a better view
我想现在获得更好的视野
of the assembly stacktrace not just the
程序集的堆栈跟踪不仅仅是
stack trace so again keep in mind we've
堆栈跟踪，因此请再次记住我们
got the assembly of data right that
正确地收集了数据
assembly of data pulls together our
数据汇编将我们的
execution that happens across different
跨不同的执行
threads so I'm not I'm not I don't want
线程，所以我不是我不是我不要
to stack trace the stack trace doesn't
堆栈跟踪堆栈跟踪不
make any sense
有道理
stack trace is by definition in a string
根据定义，堆栈跟踪为字符串
in a in a in a single thread right I
在一个单线程中
want the the execution I want the error
想要执行我想要的错误
that shows me the graph of how the error
告诉我错误的图形
happened
发生了
from the very beginning across all the
从一开始就
different threads all the way to where
不同的线程一直到哪里
we are right which is more than a thread
我们是对的，这不仅仅是一个线程
trail a thread stack trace so in this
跟踪线程堆栈跟踪，因此在此
case I have a couple of options here I
如果我在这里有两个选择
can use hooks oh by the way before I
可以在我之前用钩子哦
forget I didn't mean to forget one thing
忘记我不是要忘记一件事
you can also do this you can do on you
你也可以做到这一点
can do the check point
可以做检查点
okay and so you can actually say I wanna
好，所以你实际上可以说我想
want an error to show this message and I
想要显示此消息的错误，我
can say force with a stack trace okay so
可以说用堆栈跟踪强制好吗
when this when it gets to this part it's
当这涉及到这一部分时
gonna force in this pipeline in this in
会在这个管道中强迫
this point in the pipeline it's going to
管道中的这一点
log out the data log out a string and
注销数据注销字符串，然后
then thrown a log out a stack trace so I
然后抛出一个日志退出堆栈跟踪，所以我
can say okay log out you know capital
可以说可以退出，知道资本
letters okay lowercase letters okay so
字母还可以，小写字母
I'm giving myself breakpoint information
我给自己断点信息
here let's run this oh right
在这里让我们运行这个哦对
so
所以
okay so we get to
好，所以我们去
we get to this final checkpoint here
我们在这里到达最后的检查站
that's the last one I guess that's the
那是最后一个，我想那是
one that gets shown here so we can see I
一个显示在这里，所以我们可以看到我
want an error to show this message there
想要一个错误来显示此消息
it is there it is there it is so you can
它在那里，那里在那里，所以你可以
see that we get this like output I guess
看到我们得到这样的输出，我猜
I guess the last checkpoint is the one
我想最后一个检查点就是那个
that gets honored I'm not really quite
真的很荣幸
sure about that
可以肯定的
oh no that's why it's confusing it's got
哦，不，这就是为什么令人困惑的原因
the UM I told I said both I told both to
我告诉我的UM，我都说过
show me a stack trace so actually I
给我看一下堆栈跟踪
don't need this let's see what happens
不需要这个让我们看看会发生什么
without those
没有那些
okay Check Point
好吧，检查点
so this is the only checkpoint is that
所以这是唯一的检查点是
better did I actually show less stack
更好的是，我实际上显示了更少的堆栈
traces I feel like I have the same
痕迹，我觉得自己一样
number of stack traces okay anyway I
堆栈跟踪的数量还可以吗
don't mean to get lost on that all I'm
并不是要迷失我所拥有的一切
trying to say is the checkpoint is the
试图说是检查站是
thing that shows errors it shows up
出现错误的东西
after there I've been errors so this is
在发生错误之后，这是
the first checkpoint by which there's an
第一个检查点
exception okay so this is the one that
异常好，所以这是那个
we see I've got checkpoints here and if
我们看到我在这里有检查站，如果
there had been errors in this or this
这个或这个有错误
then we would have seen these
那么我们会看到这些
checkpoints okay
检查点还可以
I'm not sure what the force I'm not sure
我不确定我不确定什么力量
what this show stacktrace thing is
这个显示stacktrace的东西是什么
buying me actually that's why it's a
其实买我就是这就是为什么
little confused either way we've got
有点困惑，我们有
checkpoint that's very useful but I
检查点非常有用，但我
still want the assembly stacktrace
仍然想要程序集stacktrace
that's what I was trying to talk about
那就是我想要谈论的
before I want the ability to see the
在我想要看到的能力之前
bigger picture I want to see how things
我想看大图
assemble in such a way as to arrive at
以到达的方式组装
this particular error this particular
这个特殊的错误这个特殊的
sort of congealing of data of stream
流数据的凝结
data to arrive at this particular kind
数据到达这种特定种类
of error so one way to do that is to use
错误，所以一种方法是使用
a hook that you can add for reactive
可以添加用于反应的钩子
code so you can say hooks dot on debug
代码，以便您可以在调试时说钩点
or operator debug okay and and then we
或操作员调试好，然后我们
start
开始
okay so now much more useful you can see
好吧，现在您可以看到更多有用的信息
that here's the exception okay go down
那是个例外，好吧，下去
we can see the trace so we can see that
我们可以看到痕迹，所以我们可以看到
the error happened in the map operator
地图操作员中发生错误
right right there right I don't have to
对，对，对，我不必
we don't know there's no disconnect
我们不知道没有断开
between where this came from and
从何处来
actually I think it would be more useful
实际上我认为这样会更有用
if we showed this version just so we can
如果我们显示这个版本只是为了
understand that we're pulling data down
了解我们正在提取数据
from a particular place let's try that
从特定的地方尝试
again
再次
oh look at them if that are equals in
哦，看看他们是否相等
your case keep that comped it out
你的案子让它弥补了
okay so here we have same thing we can
好吧，所以在这里我们可以做同样的事情
see that flat map is where the error
看到平面图是哪里的错误
happened right and we can see the method
发生正确，我们可以看到方法
in flux Java that corresponds to flat
在对应于flat的flux Java中
map and we can see that that was invoked
地图，我们可以看到它被调用了
in go so again we're not there's no
再来一次，我们不是没有
guarantee that this will happen in the
确保这会在
same thread as go right we've in fact
事实上，与正确的线程相同
quite the contrary we pretty sure it's
相反，我们很确定这是
not gonna execute in the same thread as
不会在与同一线程中执行
go right and yet we can still see that
向右走，但我们仍然可以看到
it started here and then it ended there
它从这里开始，然后到那里结束
and the reason is because we have this
原因是因为我们有这个
hooks on operator debug that information
钩上操作员调试该信息
shows us if it shows us at first the X
告诉我们是否先显示X
it shows the exception first which is
它首先显示了异常
something in some helpful information
一些有用的信息
and then it shows us the thread stack
然后它向我们展示了线程堆栈
trace that is only the flow of execution
跟踪只是执行流程
on a given thread which isn't super
在给定的线程不是超级
useful for reactive programming but the
对于反应式编程很有用，但是
following section provides information
以下部分提供信息
about the assembly trace of the
关于装配轨迹
publisher so here we can confirm that
发布商，因此我们可以在此处确认
the error was first generated in the in
错误最初是在中产生的
the flat map method which then of course
平面图方法
links to the go method right the
链接到go方法的右侧
operators in the third section rather in
第三部分中的运算符
the third section we finally see here
第三部分我们终于在这里看到
where it was all observed right so we
在那里都被正确观察到了，所以我们
can see that the operator observed the
可以看到操作员观察到了
error we can see that we can see in this
错误，我们可以看到，我们可以看到
section sorry we can see in this section
对不起，我们可以在本节中看到
the operators that observe the error
观察错误的操作员
after the air was first triggered and in
在第一次触发空气之后
which user class they were they were
他们是哪个用户类别
triggered and what enchained
触发和束缚
and the way to do this the way we do
以及我们这样做的方式
this is actually by adding a lot of
这实际上是通过添加很多
extra weight to the publisher right so
对发布者来说是额外的重量，所以
basically there's a lot of
基本上有很多
instrumentation a lot of extra
仪表很多额外的
information that has to be created
必须创建的信息
basically we create an exception we
基本上我们创建一个异常
create a stack trace each for each
为每个创建一个堆栈跟踪
operator and then we attach it to the
运算符，然后将其附加到
operator and that gets perpetuated and
运算符，并将其永久保存，
so then later on when something goes
所以后来当事情发生时
wrong we can call all that together and
错误的，我们可以一起调用所有这些，
and then use it to build up this this
然后用它来建立这个
assembly graph but that's a lot of
装配图，但这很多
runtime overhead okay that runtime
运行时开销好吗
overhead may
开销可能
not be desirable I don't think it's
不理想，我不认为这是
desirable in production for example but
例如在生产中理想，但
you still want this information this
您仍然需要此信息
information is really useful so we have
信息真的很有用，所以我们有
an agent ish kind of thing I don't think
我不认为经纪人有这种事
it's technically strictly speaking a
从技术上讲严格来说
Java agent but it has the same effect
Java代理，但效果相同
which is that it pre processes the code
这是它预处理代码
of the application in the class loader
类加载器中应用程序的代码
before the application starts up and
在应用程序启动之前
that's called the reactor debug agent
这就是所谓的反应堆调试代理
and you can add it to your build if
您可以将其添加到您的构建中，如果
you're using them you know if you or
您正在使用它们，您是否知道
don't already have the milestone or
还没有里程碑或
snapshot dependencies make sure you do
快照依赖关系确保您执行
we started with our project under start
我们从开始的项目开始
at Springdale using spring shafts spring
在Springdale使用Spring 轴spring
snapshots and spring milestones and so
快照和春季里程碑等
with that in place all I really need to
有了这些，我真正需要的就是
do is to add the reactor tools
要做的就是添加反应堆工具
dependency okay and this will I hope I
依赖好吧，我希望我能
hope this will get merged into the main
希望这将合并到主要
of reactor core later on but for now
反应堆堆芯稍后但现在
it's a separate thing not a big deal
这是一件单独的事，没什么大不了的
okay
好的
all right so dependency IO dot all right
好的，所以依赖IO点好了
it's uh reactor tools and it's I did
这是反应堆工具，是我做的
this one so don't do that it's not that
这个不要做那不是那个
tools it's IO project reactor that's it
工具就是IO项目反应堆
okay dot M one you add this and then you
好吧，点一个，你加上这个然后你
install it so now instead of doing this
现在就安装它，而不要这样做
I can say reactor debug agent dot init
我可以说反应堆调试代理点初始化
reactor debug agent dot process existing
反应堆调试代理点过程已存在
classes this is good III in theory I
在理论上这是很好的III
don't need this for my application but
我的应用程序不需要这个，但是
uh I'm gonna go ahead and leave it there
嗯，我要继续把它留在那里
anyway okay I think I do need it I'm not
反正好吧，我想我确实需要它，我不是
sure why so okay we're gonna hit run
确定为什么会这样，我们要开始运行
like in theory you can do this later on
从理论上讲，您可以稍后再进行此操作
for example after public static void
例如在公共静态无效之后
main has started so you've got existing
主要已经开始，所以你已经存在
code that's starting the application and
启动应用程序的代码
you don't need to do this if you go
如果你去就不需要这样做
before but um I think you do it seems
之前，但嗯，我想你似乎
like I need to for my spring boot stuff
就像我需要 spring boot 一样
so for your purposes just do this you
因此，出于您的目的，请执行此操作
know worst case it's a slightly extra
知道最坏的情况是有点多余
slower on the startup okay
启动慢一点好吗
so there you go there's the actual
所以你去那里是实际的
there's the whole stack trace right this
这里有整个堆栈跟踪
is the actual and what this does is it
是实际的，它是做什么的
it rewrites your opera your your
它重写你的歌剧你
publisher your reactive stream and sort
发布您的反应流并进行排序
of makes it in at
使得它在
the at the bytecode level right so
在字节码级别正确
that's cool right you've got now same
那很酷，现在您已经拥有了
kind of information as we had before
像以前一样的信息
without having to build that entire
无需构建整个
without having to build all that extra
无需额外建造
information at runtime so that makes it
在运行时提供信息
faster it's in theory you could actually
从理论上讲，您实际上可以
take that into production obviously
显然将其投入生产
should change your logging accordingly I
应该相应地更改您的日志记录
like the reactor debug agent because it
像反应堆调试代理一样，因为它
just gives me safety you know it's like
只是给我安全，你知道这就像
it's a fairly good middle-of-the-road
这是一条相当不错的路
compromise between extra runtime
额外的运行时间之间的折衷
information and slightly slower startup
信息，启动速度稍慢
time
时间
but in exchange I get much more insight
但是作为交换，我得到了更多的见识
and then I pay a real penalty there um
然后我在那里支付实际罚款
one thing that people often ask about is
人们经常问的一件事是
well how do I know if I'm writing truly
好吧，我怎么知道我是否真的在写
reactive code what if I'm dealing with
反应性代码，如果我正在处理
something that that in turn blocks right
反过来阻止的东西
so you know what do I do i how do I make
所以你知道我该怎么做我该怎么做
sure that that's actually working as I
确保这实际上像我一样
expect it to right if I've got reactive
如果我反应灵敏，期望它是对的
code and for some reason it's slowing
代码，由于某种原因它正在变慢
down or I'm getting memory starvation
倒或者我的内存不足
I'm running out of threads that tells me
我用尽了线程告诉我
that something in the pipeline isn't
管道中的东西不是
playing fair it's actually stealing time
公平地说实际上是在偷时间
on the thread when it should just be as
在线程上时它应该只是
quick as possible right the whole point
尽可能的快一点
of this reactive paradigm is that we
这种反应性范式是
don't have a lot of threads because each
没有很多线程，因为每个线程
thread is an event loop you've got to
线程是您必须执行的事件循环
select your thread which then dispatches
选择您的线程，然后分派
to some other thread and you do the work
到其他线程，您就可以完成工作
on there very quickly and you get off
很快就到了
right so you have very you know you have
对，所以你有你知道的
very few threads in total and this only
总共只有很少的线程，这仅
works if the work you're doing is
如果您正在做的工作是可行的
asynchronous i/o and that can be done
异步I / O，可以做到
off thread basically and you will find
基本脱线，您会发现
that if you try and integrate blocking
如果您尝试整合封锁
code into your API and then you try and
代码输入您的API，然后尝试
deploy that it might even work this is
部署它甚至可以工作，这是
the most insidious part it might even
它甚至可能是最阴险的部分
work in your development environment but
在您的开发环境中工作，但
when you deploy to production you'll
当您部署到生产中时，您将
notice that you're starving for threads
请注意，您正在饿死线程
right because you've got scale now right
对，因为您现在有了规模
and so this is where you've got to be
所以这是你必须要做的
very careful so we have a really crazy
非常小心，所以我们真的很疯狂
amazing piece of software here called
令人称奇的软件
block count developed by one of our team
我们的团队之一开发的阻止计数
members
成员
sergej and block pound is just insane it
sergej和块磅简直是疯了
actually does some native code as well
实际上也做一些本机代码
but it doesn't you know it's it's just
但你不知道那只是
done so I look what they that you don't
做完了，我看看你不喜欢的东西
need to worry about that so here's what
需要担心的是，这就是
I'm gonna do I'm gonna install a block
我要安装块
down like that m3 so that's under
像那Spring Cloud Contract一样向下
project reactive tools not in the same
项目反应工具不一样
package as reactor tools which is a wee
作为反应堆工具包装
bit confusing and you bring that in by
有点混乱，你把它带进来
just saying block count install so here
只是说块计数安装所以在这里
okay
好的
actually it doesn't matter I guess I
其实没关系，我猜我
haven't you know I suppose that's
你不知道我想那是
probably fine
可能还好
but now keep it simple one when this
但是现在保持简单
thing to look at well count
值得一看的东西
I feel like
我感觉像
yeah should just be blackout I am
是的，我应该停电
confused okay let's see let's see go to
困惑好吧，让我们看看，让我们看看
this one yeah it's there may even
这是的，甚至有可能
re-import I'm gonna sworn I were to set
重新导入我要宣誓要设定
it up at some point but let's just see
在某个时候，但让我们看看
well that's confusing in it so we're
好吧，这令人困惑，所以我们
looking for the right version of walk
寻找合适的步行方式
ound I've got I'll project reactive
我知道我会做出反应
tools block count one but om3 and I've
工具阻止了一个，但om3和我已经
got the snapshots
得到了快照
seems like that should be there
似乎应该在那里
look how oh there it is okay
看看那里怎么样
now we're cooking so I just had to I
现在我们在做饭，所以我只需要
don't know shake a tree or something it
不知道摇一棵树或其他东西
it's now finally working good okay so
现在终于可以正常工作了，所以
now I've got black on that install this
现在我已经安装了黑色
takes a block count integration and
进行块计数集成
there's actually different you can use
实际上可以使用不同
bloodhound without reactor it just it
没有反应堆的猎犬
detects blocking code anywhere you want
在您想要的任何地方检测阻止代码
it to right there's a default block
它在右边有一个默认块
hound integration that gets loaded and
猎犬集成，并加载
contributed automatically for reactor
自动为反应堆贡献
right you can see block at reactor block
正确，您可以在反应堆块上看到块
count integration there's also one for
计数集成还有一个
arcs Java 2 right and so you can use you
正确地实现了Java 2，因此您可以使用它
know whatever you want there's a lot of
知道你想要什么，有很多
different ones there there's one for
不同的有一个
logging if you have a phone log where
记录是否有电话记录
that's blocking you can detect that by
这可以阻止您通过
default the one that that's available
默认一个可用的
for for for reactor is already loaded
for for反应堆已经加载
because block count uses a service
因为块计数使用服务
loader mechanism so you can see here in
加载程序机制，因此您可以在这里看到
this package it says meta imp services
这个包装上写着meta imp services
reactor block count integration by count
反应器块计数（按计数）积分
integration and just loads this class so
集成并加载此类
the Java six service load or API results
Java六个服务负载或API结果
in loading this class which gets
在加载该类时
registered automatically and that
自动注册，然后
automatically registers the right
自动注册权利
integration for for reactor so you don't
用于反应堆的集成，因此您无需
need to do that yourself but you could
需要自己做，但是你可以
provide other reactive integrations here
在此处提供其他反应式集成
you can actually override or whatever or
您实际上可以覆盖或其他
you can just leave it like that which is
您可以像这样留下它
the default which is what we're going to
默认值就是我们要
do and now we're gonna change our code
现在，我们要更改代码
here a little bit we're gonna actually
在这里，我们实际上会
create a blocking API okay so let's get
创建一个阻塞的API好吧，让我们开始吧
rid of the error so we can let's just
消除错误，让我们可以
well here actually it's just to comment
好吧，这里实际上只是评论
that out good stuff alright
好东西好了
good so now I'm just returning the
好，所以现在我只返回
letter always okay there's no error
信总是可以的，没有错误
it'll never be a problem everything will
永远不会成为问题，一切都会
continue happily and we can focus on
继续快乐，我们可以专注于
bigger better things or what happened
更大更好的事情或发生了什么
there good stuff okay
有好东西好吗
so now I am now gonna block and we could
所以现在我要阻止了，我们可以
a an API that blocks now keep in mind
现在记住的API
here I'm scheduled I'm subscribing on a
在这里，我预定的是
different thread
不同的线程
okay I'm subscribing a different thread
好吧，我正在订阅其他线程
pool that's scheduler is what allows
调度程序池是允许的
reactor to figure out on what threads it
反应器找出它的螺纹
can run this code now when you use a
现在可以在使用
scheduler in in reactor schedulers are
反应堆调度程序中的调度程序是
backed by usually you know thread pools
通常，您知道线程池
of some sort but there are different
某种形式，但有不同
kinds of thread pool certain they're not
各种线程池（肯定不是）
all created equal okay so if you're
所有人都平等，好吧，如果你是
using elastic for example then then
例如使用弹性然后
sorry if using elastic the scheduler
对不起，如果使用弹性调度程序
elastic this is meant to scale out all
弹性这意味着可以扩展所有
right this is a scheduler that's meant
对，这是一个调度程序
to scale out as much as it needs to and
根据需要扩展
so the whole point there is I have
所以我要说的是
something that's gonna block and thus is
会阻塞的东西
gonna necess to Tait the use of more
需要更多使用
threads and so I need I'm fully prepared
线程，所以我需要充分准备
for this to scale out or you know as
以便扩大规模，或者您知道
much as needed I'm fully prepared for
我已经准备充分了
something to block so if you have
东西要封锁，所以如果你有
something you're gonna do with a JDBC
您将要使用JDBC进行的操作
datasource or something then you use
数据源或您使用的东西
this the elastic schedule because it'll
这是弹性的时间表，因为它会
it'll it'll do the right thing there
它会在那里做正确的事
okay obviously this means that your
好吧，这显然意味着您
application is now constrained by your
应用程序现在受到您的限制
ability to add a handle to add more
能够添加手柄以添加更多
threats you've lost a lot of the big
威胁已经失去了很多
benefits of using you know a reactive
使用你的好处知道反应
API okay so cash in turn create a thread
API可以，因此现金又可以创建一个线程
pool where's all this code schedulers
这些代码调度程序在哪里
let's see not
让我们看看
non-blocking yes instance of
的非阻塞yes实例
non-blocking you can see find usages
非阻塞，您可以看到查找用法
some threads some threads that are
一些线程
created by thread pools that are
由线程池创建
blocking or rather that are not blocking
阻止，或者说不阻止
those threads will will descend from
这些线程将从
another class that in turn has this
另一个班级有这个
interface and you can detect that okay
界面，您可以检测到
so if you're wondering about which skin
所以如果您想知道哪种皮肤
which third which schedulers are
哪个调度程序是哪三分之一
blocking and which ones are not blocking
阻止和哪些没有阻止
friendly
友好
this one is a blocking friendly
这是一个友好的封锁
scheduler so this won't cause any issues
调度程序，所以这不会引起任何问题
but let's say that I want to have one
但是我想有一个
that will that will air out right
那会消失的权利
something that will definitely cause an
肯定会导致
issue because it's the limit it's not
问题，因为这不是极限
gonna create new threads ad infinitum so
将无限地创建新线程，因此
here I'm gonna create a thread pool
在这里我要创建一个线程池
limit it's a ten thread actually you
限制它实际上是十个线程
know you shouldn't have more threads and
知道你不应该有更多的线程
you have cores for example in this case
例如，在这种情况下，您有核心
and by the way by default you're you've
顺便说一下，默认情况下，您已经
got a scheduler that is just constrained
有一个受限制的调度程序
to how many how many CPUs we've got how
我们有多少个CPU
many cores you've got so you shouldn't
你有很多核心，所以你不应该
need to do this but if you want to
需要这样做，但是如果你想
override that you can so here I'm gonna
覆盖你可以的，所以我在这里
say okay let's subscribe on this
说好吧，让我们订阅这个
schedule schedule okay and what I want
安排好时间表，我要什么
to do is on a block I'm gonna create
我要做的是创建一个街区
something it'll it'll actually end up
它会最终结束
blocking the flow of execution so in
阻碍执行流程
order to block I'm gonna create a method
为了阻止我要创建一个方法
here called void block and void block
这里称为空块和空块
well just block I'm gonna sleep
好吧，我要睡觉了
arbitrarily for a second and this is
任意一秒钟，这是
going to be a thing that'll throw an
将会扔出一个东西
exception so I'm gonna use Lombok to
例外，所以我要用龙目岛
just swallow the exception or you know
吞下例外，否则你就知道
to hide it so I don't this gonna wrap
隐藏它，所以我不会把它包起来
this in a try-catch and then I'm gonna
尝试一下，然后我要
do a flat map okay so I'm gonna flat map
做一个平面图好吧，我要去平面图
I'm gonna do a doing next that's even
我要去做的下一个甚至
better I don't have to be any work so
更好，我不必做任何工作，所以
this
这个
I feel like that should be it
我觉得应该是这样
good yes okay so I'm just eat for each
好，是的，所以我只是每个人都吃
record that is it is consumed I'm gonna
记录它被消耗了，我要
slow down the processing on the third
减慢第三步的处理
I'm gonna sit on the thread that we're
我要坐在我们的线程上
using on the third pool and that we know
在第三个池中使用，我们知道
that that thread pool is gonna be a
该线程池将成为一个
can't block that bore each thread in
不能阻止每个线程
this new parallel foot pool is you know
你知道这个新的平行脚池吗
there's only five fish so if you're
只有五条鱼，所以如果你是
blocking somebody's gonna be starved of
阻止某人饿死
engine as soon as you get six requests
收到六个请求后立即启动引擎
you're not gonna be able to use that so
你将无法使用它，所以
the block eight block count will detect
块八块计数将检测
that first let's try it out
首先让我们尝试一下
cool I've got a lot of errors we should
很酷，我有很多错误，我们应该
block and call there you go
封锁并呼叫您去
jaw line error blocking call and you can
下颌线错误阻止呼叫，您可以
actually see that in turn turned into an
实际看到又变成了
error in the pipeline which the rest of
管道中其余的错误
the the rest of the error handling code
其余的错误处理代码
that we put in actually catches so
我们实际捕捉到的
that's kind of cool so they go so you
那很酷，所以他们走了，所以你
can you have to see this is where we're
你能看到这是我们的地方吗
spending our time somebody's making a
花我们的时间有人正在
call to this and you know we can see
打电话给你，你知道我们可以看到
that blood count is instrumented our
血液计数是我们的工具
code there and we can see that it's
代码在那里，我们可以看到它是
actually happening in block isn't it
实际发生在不是吗
cool
凉
so now we have the ability to find where
所以现在我们有能力找到
we're blocking in the pipeline right
我们正在阻塞管道
even if it's somebody else's API and
即使是别人的API和
it's blocking now let's just just to
现在被阻止了
show it to show you what I'm talking
展示给你看我在说什么
about
关于
actually I just changed this well do
其实我只是改好了
this a can block so new it's not elastic
这可以阻止这么新，它没有弹性
there you go just you can block okay we
你去那里就可以阻止我们
start this
开始这个
so there you go now that's
所以你现在就去
behind-the-scenes we're creating a new
幕后，我们正在创建一个新的
thread you can see it says right here
线程，你可以看到它说在这里
thread 1 2 3 4 5 6 and I would if I had
线程1 2 3 4 5 6，如果我有
a trillion records it would keep trying
一万亿条记录，它将继续尝试
to create new threads as long as it
创建新线程，只要它
needed to to process the data right
需要处理数据权
because you know we'd went out of we
因为你知道我们会走出我们
would have every that we would be using
将拥有我们将要使用的所有东西
all the other ones at any given time so
在任何给定时间的所有其他
that's not a good approach and you
那不是一个好方法，你
should be careful about that you should
应该注意
test whether that thread that you're
测试您是否正在使用该线程
running on is elastic by using the the
通过使用
scheduler is is a is blocking threads
调度程序是一个正在阻止线程
right ok I think that's it I think we've
好的，我想就是我想
covered just about everything I can
几乎涵盖了我所能
imagine wanting to show you I think I
想像要给你看我想我
hope you got something out of this I
希望你从中得到一些东西
hope in our journey today you saw some
希望今天我们在旅途中看到一些
tool that'll help you out
可以帮助您的工具
basically these the reactive debug agent
基本上这些反应式调试代理
and block and are your friends they're
封锁，是你的朋友，他们是
their agents actually pre process code
他们的代理商实际上在处理代码
or bytecode right there it process they
或字节码在那里处理
work at the class loader if you will
如果愿意，可以在类加载器上工作
level not at the runtime level so
级别不在运行时级别，因此
they're actually fairly efficient I
他们实际上是相当有效的
can't say that they don't add any
不能说他们不添加任何东西
overhead but they're they're better than
开销，但他们比
not having a way to discover there's
没有办法发现那里的
certain thing and even if you only use
某些事情，即使您只使用
them in development time you know
他们在开发时就知道
there's gonna be some benefit there and
那里会有一些好处，
if you do if use in production you know
如果您将其用于生产，则知道
you know what you're doing and it needs
你知道你在做什么，需要什么
to have the ability to recover it's all
有能力恢复一切
about how you can gracefully degrade and
关于如何优雅地降级以及
and you know I think these api's are
而且你知道我认为这些api是
really powerful right this is not much
真的很强大，这并不多
more complicated than Java eight stream
比Java 8流更复杂
API right you're not actually doing
您实际上没有做的API权利
things that are much worse or more
更糟或更严重的事情
complicated than the Java streams API
比Java Streams API复杂
it's just that you get a better scale
只是您获得了更好的规模
right you get better scale than if you
对，你得到的规模比
wrote synchronous or or blocking code I
写了同步或阻塞代码我
appreciate you listening as always and
感谢您一如既往的倾听，
you know if you like this please
你知道你是否喜欢这个
obviously leave a thumbs up or a comment
显然竖起大拇指或发表评论
on the on the video and as always thanks
在视频上，一如既往的感谢
again we'll see you next time
下次我们再见
you
您